-=TLF字幕組=- 榮譽出品
翻譯：飛翔的雞
翻譯：Jason Lee
翻譯：versus
君臨
King's Landing
翻譯：Hello_Agnes
翻譯&校對：lydia萌
特效：飛翔的雞
統籌：飯離燁
恐怖堡
Dreadfort
臨冬城
WinterFell
絕境長城
The Wall
布拉佛斯
Braavos
彌林
Meereen
根據喬治·R·R·馬丁著《冰與火之歌》改編
權力的遊戲
第四季   第七集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
榮譽出品
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
電視劇編劇
戴維·貝尼奧夫 & D·B·威斯
導演
埃裏克·薩哈洛夫
I made a deal for you to keep your ungrateful head
我為你跟父親做交易，讓你忘恩負義的腦袋
學舌鳥
on your ungrateful neck a little while longer.
在你忘恩負義脖子上多呆一會
I'm sorry, what am I grateful for?
<i>抱歉，我該感謝什麼？</i>
The opportunity to live and die at the Wall
在長城待到死
as punishment for a crime I did not commit?
作為我莫須有罪名的懲罰？
You threw your life away. You threw it away.
你自己放棄了生命，自己放棄了
It's not a joke. You understand that, don't you?
這不是開玩笑，你懂嗎？
Of course it's a joke, just not a very funny one.
這當然是玩笑，只是不怎麼好笑
I couldn't--
我無法…
I couldn't listen to her
我無法聽她
standing there telling her lies.
站在那滿嘴謊言
I couldn't do it.
我做不到
You fell in love with a whore.
你愛上了一個妓女
Yes, I fell in love with a whore.
是，我愛上了一個妓女
And I was stupid enough to think that she had fallen in love with me.
而且我還愚蠢地以為她也愛我
That deal you made,
你做的交易
it was everything Father wanted.
是父親畢生所願
You do see that?
<i>你知道嗎？</i>
He gets you back as his heir.
<i>他有你做繼承人</i>
The future Lord of the Rock.
<i>未來的凱巖城領主</i>
And he ships me off to Castle Black,
然後把我發配到黑城堡
out of sight at last.
終於不用見到我了
All so perfect.
一切都那麼完美
It felt good to take that from him.
把這些從他手裏奪去感覺真好
He knows I'm innocent and he's willing to sacrifice me anyway.
他知道我是無辜的，他還願意犧牲我
He's willing to sacrifice any of us.
他願意犧牲我們所有人
Not you.
除了你
You're the golden son.
你是他的愛子
You could kill a king, lose a hand,
就算你殺了國王，丟了一隻手
fuck your own sister, you'll always be the golden son.
上了你親姐姐，你還是他的愛子
Careful.
小心點
I'm the last friend you've got.
你就只有我這一個朋友了
At least I got to tell them what they really are.
至少我終於揭穿了他們的真面目
Yes, brilliant speech.
對，出色的演講
They'll be talking about it for days to come.
他們會談論上幾天的
I thought you were a realist.
<i>我一直以為你是現實主義者</i>
Didn't realize you'd die for pride.
沒想到你會為尊嚴而死
Don't give up on me just yet.
先別對我絕望
I survived one trial by combat,
我在上次比武審判中活下來了
even though you weren't there to save me.
即使你沒來救我
I can't save you this time either.
這次我也不能救你
My training has proved
<i>我的訓練已經證明了</i>
that I can't beat a stable boy with my left hand.
我用左手連個馬童都打不贏
Where's your sense of adventure?
你的冒險精神哪去了？
Even if you lose, imagine the look
即使你輸了，想想
on Father's face when you fall.
你倒下時候父親的表情
Our family name snuffed out
一劍砍下
with a single swing of the sword.
我們家族就滅絕了
It is tempting.
很誘人啊
Well...
那麼…
Bronn fought for me once, he'll do it again.
波隆為我戰鬥過，他可以再戰
If he wins,
如果他贏了
I expect I'll be in his debt
我會一生
for the rest of my life.
都欠他人情
If he wins.
如果他能贏
Will you find him for me?
你能替我找到他嗎？
Who does Cersei plan on naming as a champion?
瑟曦準備讓誰代表？
I hope it's Ser Meryn Trant.
我希望是馬林·特蘭爵士
I'd enjoy watching Bronn disembowel that pompous child beater.
我想看波隆開了那浮誇傢伙的膛
No.
不是
Not Ser Meryn.
不是馬林爵士
Go on, move it.
<i>繼續</i>
And you.
到你了
Come on.
快點
Mercy.
求你了
Please.
Please, mercy.
求你饒了我吧
Ser Gregor. Welcome to the capital.
格雷果爵士，歡迎來都城
Thank you for riding here so quickly.
感謝你這麼快就到了
You seem to be in good form.
你看來狀態不錯
Who am I fighting?
我的對手是誰？
Does it matter?
有關係嗎？
Could be food.
可能有吃的
Could be soldiers.
可能有士兵
You shouldn't be sitting out here like this.
你不能這樣坐在這兒
Where else to sit?
還能坐哪？
Tried to walk back to my hut,
試過回我的小屋
hurt too much.
但傷太重
Then I remembered they burned my hut down.
然後我想起來他們把我的小屋燒了
Who were "they"?
他們是誰？
I stopped asking a while ago.
我已經放棄追究了
That's not gonna get better.
這傷口不會好的
Doesn't seem so.
不像能好
A bad way to go.
會越來越糟
Haven't you had enough?
你還沒受夠嗎？
Of what?
受夠什麼？
I know.
知道了
Time to go.
是時候了
Take matters into my own hands.
我想自己解決
The thought has occurred to me.
我有這樣想過
So why go on?
為什麼還堅持？
Habit.
習慣
Nothing could be worse than this.
沒有什麼能比這更糟了
Maybe nothing is worse than this.
也許「沒有了」比這更糟
Nothing isn't better or worse than anything.
「沒有了」不比任何事更好或更糟
Nothing is just nothing.
沒有了就是沒有了
Who are you?
你是誰？
My name is Arya.
我叫艾莉亞
Arya Stark.
艾莉亞·史塔克
You her father?
你是她父親？
Her captor.
她是我的俘虜
Bringing her to her aunt for ransom.
我帶她去她姨媽家要贖金
A fair exchange, that is.
公平交換
Always held to the notion of fair exchange
凡是我做生意
in all my dealings.
都堅守公平交換原則
You give me, I give you.
你給我要的，我給你要的
Fair.
<i>買賣公平</i>
A balance.
平衡互利
No balance anymore.
再無平衡可言了
Could I have a drink?
能給我喝一口嗎？
Dying is thirsty work.
等死叫人口渴
Wish it were wine.
要是酒就好了
So do I.
我也希望
That's where the heart is.
這才是心臟的位置
That's how you kill a man.
這才是殺人的正確方法
The fuck you doing?
你們他媽搞什麼？
There's a price on your head.
<i>拿你的人頭有賞錢</i>
Guess that's what the king does when you tell him to fuck off.
我猜是因為我罵國王去他媽的
The king's dead.
國王死了
He drank poisoned wine at his own wedding.
<i>他在婚宴上喝了毒酒</i>
The bounty on you is for killing Lannister soldiers.
你殺了蘭尼斯特的士兵，所以懸賞你
100 silver stags.
一百個銀鹿幣
And you thought you were going to collect it?
你以為你能領到手嗎？
Didn't think very hard, did you?
<i>沒想清楚是吧？</i>
You were Yoren's prisoners when he was taking me to the Wall.
尤倫帶我去長城的時候，你是他的犯人
He told me he'd fuck me bloody with a stick.
他說會用根棍子把我搞死
This day's really not working out the way you planned.
真沒想到在這裏冤家路窄了
He on your little list?
你名單上有他嗎？
He can't be.
不可能有
I don't know his name.
我不知道他的名字
What's your name?
你叫什麼？
- Rorge. - Thank you.
- 羅爾傑
- 謝謝
You're learning.
孺子可教
Rangers returning!
<i>守夜人回來啦！</i>
They return!
<i>他們回來啦！</i>
- Rangers returning! - Greetings.
- <i>守夜人回來啦！</i>
- 別來無恙
Didn't think I'd see you again.
<i>還以為我再也</i>
<i>見不到你了</i>
All right, Jon?
挺好的吧，瓊恩
Welcome back, brother.
歡迎歸來，兄弟
Lord Snow.
雪諾大人
This is no place for wild beasts.
<i>野獸可不能待在這裏</i>
Lock him away
把它關起來
or I'll let Hobb throw him in tonight's stew.
否則我讓哈布拿它燉湯
Come on, Ghost.
來吧，白靈
Mance's army was closing in on Craster's Keep when we left.
我們離開時，曼斯的軍隊正逼近卡斯特堡
We saw their campfires from Osric's Hill.
我們從歐斯裏克山看到他們的篝火
They'll reach the Wall before the next full moon.
他們會趕在下次月圓前到達長城
I'm surprised you didn't ride over and say hello.
你竟然沒跑去打聲招呼
The King-beyond-the-Wall is your old friend, isn't he?
塞外之王是你的故交，不是嗎？
We need to prepare.
我們要有防備
We've been preparing.
我們一直在防備
We should seal the tunnel.
我們應該把隧道封起來
Plug it with rocks and ice.
用石頭和冰塊堵起來
Flood it and let it freeze.
往裏面灌水，讓它凍住
And how would we range north?
<i>那我們如何去北方巡邏？</i>
- We wouldn't. - Coward.
- 不去
<i>- 你個懦夫</i>
You would cut off our legs,
你想砍下我們的雙腿
pluck out our eyes,
剜出我們雙眼
leave us cowering behind the Wall
讓我們畏縮在長城之後
hoping for the storm to pass?
指望風暴能平息？
We can't defend the gate against 100,000 men.
與十萬大軍作戰，我們守不住城門
This castle has stood for thousands of years.
這座城堡矗立了幾千年
The Night's Watch has defended her for thousands of years.
守夜人也已捍衛了它幾千年
And in all those centuries, we have never sealed the tunnel.
千百年以來，我們從沒封過隧道
Have you ever seen a giant, Ser Alliser?
你見過巨人嗎，艾裏沙大人？
I have.
<i>我見過</i>
The tunnel's gate won't stop them.
隧道大門阻擋不住他們
The bars on those gates are four inches thick.
門閂厚四寸
Cold-rolled steel.
外包冷凝鋼
They won't stop them.
那也擋不住
Remind me which order you belong to, Lord Snow.
你到底擔任什麼職務，雪諾大人
The stewards.
事務官
Are the stewards responsible for maintaining the tunnel?
事務官是否有責任維護隧道？
No.
沒有
Who would that be?
那是誰有的職責？
- The builders. - Ah, the builders.
- 工匠
- 是啊，工匠
First Builder Yarwyck,
首席工匠亞威克
Lord Snow here recommends sealing the tunnel,
雪諾大人下令封鎖隧道
leaving us unable to carry out our duties
讓我們誓守邊關的守夜兄弟
as sworn brothers of the Night's Watch.
束手無策，坐以待斃
Do you agree with him?
你可同意？
No.
不
Given your deep knowledge of the wildling army, Lord Snow,
<i>鑒於你對蠻族軍隊的淵博知識，雪諾大人</i>
you and Tarly will take night duties atop the Wall
你和塔利負責城頭守夜
until the full moon.
直到月圓之夜
Moving on.
<i>繼續</i>
First Builder, we'll need 100 barrels of pitch brought atop the wall.
<i>首席工匠，我們要在城頭準備一百桶瀝青</i>
Aye.
<i>遵命</i>
My lord.
大人
You have new clothes.
你換了一身新行頭
Do you like 'em? Eh?
喜歡嗎？
Gloves are doeskin.
母鹿皮的手套
Softer than a virgin's thighs.
比處女的大腿還柔滑
I sent for you days ago.
<i>我好幾天前就派人找你來</i>
- I've been a bit busy. - Doing what?
- 我一直在忙
- 忙什麼？
My lonesome bachelor days are over.
我寂寞單身漢的日子到頭了
I'm to wed Lollys Stokeworth.
我要迎娶洛麗絲·史鐸克渥斯
Lollys Stokeworth?
洛麗絲·史鐸克渥斯？
She doesn't strike me as your sort of girl.
<i>我想這種姑娘並不合你的口味吧</i>
I wouldn't say I had a single sort of girl.
我不認為我對姑娘有特定口味
She's dim-witted.
她是個傻子
If I wanted wits, I'd marry you.
如果要聰明的，我就娶你好了
When my sister arranged this love match,
我姐姐安排這樁婚事的時候
did she mention that Lollys has an older sister?
她有提過洛麗絲有個姐姐嗎？
Falyse.
法麗絲
Aye, I did know about the older sister.
是的，我知道她有姐姐
And you understand the rules of inheritance?
你也明白血脈延續的規矩
Falyse is 40 and barren.
法麗絲四十歲了，無法生育
She still gets Castle Stokeworth when her father dies.
<i>她父親一死，她仍然擁有史鐸克渥斯堡</i>
She does.
是的
Unless she happens to perish before her father.
除非她死在她父親之前
Then Lollys gets the castle.
然後洛麗絲就繼承了城堡
What? Ladies fall from their horses
怎麼了？姑娘從馬上摔下來
and snap their pretty necks all the time.
弄斷脖子，這種事司空見慣了
You and my sister deserve each other.
你跟我姐可真是天生一對
Why did you bother to come here?
<i>那你幹嘛還來這？</i>
You once said if anyone ever asked me to sell you out,
你說過，要是有人想讓我出賣你
you'd double their price.
你會把價格翻倍
Is it two wives you want or two castles?
你想要兩個老婆，還是兩座城堡？
One of each will do.
哪個都行
But if you want me to kill the Mountain for you,
但如果你要我幫你殺魔山
it'd better be a damn big castle.
最好給我座無比巨大的城堡
I'm bit short on castles at the moment.
我現在手裏沒城堡
But I can offer you gold and gratitude.
不過可以給你金子和感激之情
I have gold.
我有金子
What can I buy with gratitude?
感激能買什麼東西？
You might be surprised.
你可能沒聽過
A Lannister always pays his debts.
蘭尼斯特有債必還
Your sister's a Lannister, too.
你姐姐也是蘭尼斯特的
My wife is heir to Winterfell.
我妻子是臨冬城的繼承人
If I emerge from this with my head still on my shoulders,
<i>我這次若能全身而退</i>
I may one day rule the North in her name.
<i>也許有一天我能以她的名義統治北境</i>
I could carve you out a big piece of it.
我可以分一大塊土地給你
If and may and could.
若能，也許，可以…
It's bloody cold up north.
北境冷得要命
Lollys is soft and warm.
洛麗絲溫暖柔軟
And close.
離得又近
If I gave you the choice between fucking Lollys
如果我要你選擇，是和洛麗絲上床
and fighting the Mountain, you'd have your britches down
還是和魔山決鬥，你眨眼的功夫
and your cock out before I could blink.
就嚇得褲子落地，老二橫飛了
Does he frighten you so much?
你就這麼怕他？
I'd be a bloody fool if he didn't frighten me.
我要是不怕他，我就是個傻子
He's freakish big and freakish strong.
他身強體壯，厲害得不像話
And quicker than you'd expect for a man of that size.
身材巨大，還動作敏捷，讓你猝不及防
Maybe I could take him,
或許我可以跟他周旋
dance around until he's so tired
直到他砍膩味了
of hacking at me, he dropped his sword,
劍一脫手
get him off his feet somehow.
我再把他放倒
But one misstep...
但要是有絲毫差錯…
...and I'm dead.
…那我就死翹翹了
Why should I risk it?
我為什麼要冒這個險？
Because you're my friend.
因為你是我的朋友
Aye, I'm your friend.
是啊，我是你朋友
And when have you ever risked your life for me?
而你什麼時候為我挺身而出過？
I like you,
我喜歡你
pampered little shit that you are.
儘管你為人放縱了點
I just like myself more.
但我更喜歡自己
I understand.
我理解
I'm sorry it has to be this way.
很抱歉事情發展成這樣
Why are you sorry?
為何要道歉?
Because you're an evil bastard
因為你是個沒心沒肺的
with no conscience and no heart?
邪惡私生子?
That's what I liked about you in the first place.
那正是我當初看上你的原因
We had some good days together.
我們曾經很開心
Yes, we did.
沒錯
What will you do?
你準備怎麼辦
I suppose I'll have to kill the Mountain myself.
我不得不親自殺魔山了
Won't that make for a great song?
這會被編成偉大的歌謠, 對嗎?
I hope to hear them sing it one day.
希望有朝一日我能聽到
How did you get in here?
你怎麼進來的?
Your door is well guarded,
你的大門有嚴密的守衛
but your window is not.
窗戶卻沒有
I swam to an island a mile offshore for these.
我游到了一里外的一個島上，採來了這花
Don't do that again.
別再做這種事了
Never met a woman who didn't like wildflowers.
我還沒見過不喜歡野花的女人
These are my private quarters.
這是我的私人地盤
If I want you here, I will summon you.
需要你的時候我會召喚你的
Forgive me, my queen. I live to serve you.
很抱歉，女王陛下，我活著就是為了侍奉你
Tell me why you're here.
告訴我你來這裏的目的吧
I came to ask a favor.
我有個不情之請
I only have two talents in this world--
在這個世界上，我只有兩個才能
war and women.
戰爭和女人
You are staying here in Meereen to rule.
你要留在彌林統治
That is a wise decision. I respect it.
我尊重這個英明的決定
But here in Meereen, I cannot pursue my talents.
但在彌林，我無法施展我的才能
I've ordered the Second Sons to patrol the streets
我讓次子團在街道巡邏
to stop the revenge killing.
以阻止復仇殺戮
You've ordered us to be night watchmen.
你讓我們做夜間看守
And as for women,
至於女人
there are thousands in Meereen you can pursue.
彌林有大把女人可以追求
There is only one,
只有一個
and she does not want me.
但她對我沒興趣
You swore me your sword.
你曾用劍對我起誓
My sword is yours till the day I die.
我的劍為你所用直到我生命盡頭
So if I command you to stay in Meereen
那如果我命令你在彌林
and patrol the streets?
巡視街道呢？
I'll stay in Meereen and patrol the streets.
我會在彌林巡視街道
Send me to kill your enemies.
讓我殺死你的敵人
Any enemy anywhere.
任何地方，任何敵人
Let me do what I do best.
讓我做我最擅長的事情
Very well.
很好
Do what you do best.
那就做你最擅長的事情吧
Take off your clothes.
脫掉衣服
Come in, my queen. Please.
請進來，王后
I didn't mean to disturb you, my lady.
我不是有意打擾你，夫人
You could never disturb me.
你不會打擾我
I just wanted to speak with you before we left.
只是想在我離開之前和你談談
Could you bring me that vial over there?
能幫我把那邊的瓶子拿來嗎？
The blue one.
藍色的
No, no, no. Not that one.
不不不，不是那個
You don't even want to touch that one.
你不會想碰它的
Next to it.
旁邊那個
That's the one.
就是這個
When I looked into the flames this morning,
今天早上我觀察火焰時
the Lord spoke to me.
光之王跟我說話了
He said,
他說
"Tonight, you will have your last good bath in a long while.
今晚之後的很長一段時間你都不能好好洗澡了
Make it count."
好好享受吧
A joke.
開玩笑的
Not a very good one, I'm afraid.
不是很好笑
It was. I--
挺好笑的. 我…
humor isn't my strength.
並不擅長幽默
That's because st jokes are lies
因為大多數玩笑都是謊言
and you're devoted to the truth.
而你卻致力於真實
If they're lies, my lady, aren't they best avoided?
夫人，如果這些是謊言的話，不是該避免麼？
Not always.
不總是
Most of these powders and potions
這些粉末和藥水絕大多數
are lies.
是假的
Deceptions to make men think they witnessed our Lord's power.
為了欺騙別人，讓人以為看到了光之王的力量
Once they step into his light, they will see the lie for what it was--
一旦他們走入了光之王的光芒之中
就會知道謊話背後的真實
a trick that led them to the truth.
讓他們瞭解事實的詭計
A pinch of this powder in a bonfire
在篝火中放入少許這種粉末
will send a flaming column screaming towards the sky.
就會產生直插天空的火柱
And this one creates a black smoke
這種則會產生黑色煙霧
that will make the bravest man piss himself with fear.
即使最勇敢的人看到了也會嚇得失禁
And a drop of this in any man's wine
而這種，滴一滴在酒裏
will drive him wild with lust.
就會讓男人慾火焚身
Did you use it with Stannis?
你給史坦尼斯也用了這個？
No.
沒有
Don't be upset.
不要煩心
Men never crave what they already have.
男人從不渴望已經有的東西
It's only flesh.
只是肉慾
It needs what it needs.
肉體有需要而已
No act done in service of the Lord
對大人的侍奉都不能
can ever be called a sin.
被稱為犯罪
I thank God every day for bringing you to us.
每天我都感謝諸神把你帶給我們
And Stannis to you.
以及把史坦尼斯帶給你
He wants to bring Shireen with us.
他想要帶希琳和我們一起走
I think that would be ill-advised.
我覺得這不明智
My daughter has heretical tendencies, as you're well aware.
你很清楚我女兒有異端傾向
I don't know if her doubt is real or simply meant to spite me,
我不知道她是真那麼想還是只為了頂撞我
but whichever the case, she should stay home.
但無論如何，她應該呆在家裏
I understand how you feel.
我理解你的感受
But that is impossible.
但這不可能
Why?
為什麼？
You don't need powders and potions, my queen.
你不需要粉末和藥水，王后
You don't need lies.
你不需要謊言
You are strong enough to look into the Lord's light
你足夠強大，強大到能看見光之王的光芒
and see his truth for yourself.
看到真實的情況
However harsh it is.
不管這是多麼嚴苛
However hard for us to understand.
對我們而言多麼難以理解
You don't need my help,
你不需要我的幫助
but I will need yours soon.
但很快我就會需要你幫助
When we set sail, your daughter must be with us.
我們揚帆起航的時候，你女兒必須和我們一起
The Lord needs her.
光之王需要她
Jorah the Andal.
安達爾的喬拉
Are you here to see our queen?
你來看我們的女王？
She's in a good mood.
她現在心情正好
Khaleesi.
卡麗熙
- You're here early. - Later than some.
- 你來的真早
- 不比某人早
You don't approve?
你不同意？
It's not a question of approval, it's a question of trust.
這不是同意而是信任的問題
You neither approve nor trust.
你既不同意也不信任
Why would I? The man's a sellsword.
他是個僱傭兵
Didn't you fight for the Golden Company
你在宣誓效忠我哥哥之前
before pledging your sword to my brother?
不是為黃金團幹活？
I did.
是的
I trust you.
我信任你
Daario Naharis killed his captains
達裏奧·納哈里斯，因為厭倦了團長們的命令
and dumped their heads at your feet when he grew tired of their commands.
就殺了他們並把頭扔到你的腳邊
How could you ever have faith in a man like that?
你怎麼能信任這樣的人？
I could never have faith in a man like Daario.
我永遠不會信任達裏奧這樣的人
That's why I've sent him and the Second Sons to retake Yunkai.
所以我派他和次子團去奪回淵凱
- You have? - I have.
- 是嗎？
- 是的
Without you there to rule, Khaleesi,
卡麗熙，沒有你在那裏統領
I fear the masters will simply bide their time,
我懷疑那些領主們只會拖延時間
wait for the invaders to leave and reassert control.
等侵略者們離開以後就重申控制權
That is why I've ordered Daario to execute every master in Yunkai.
因此我命令達裏奧殺死淵凱的每一個領主
The masters tear babies from their mothers' arms.
那些領主從母親們的胳膊裏搶走嬰兒
They mutilate little boys by the thousands.
殺死的小男孩數以千計
They train little girls in the art of pleasuring old men.
訓練小女孩取悅老男人
They treat men like beasts, as you said yourself.
如你所說，他們像訓野獸一樣訓練男人
Herding the masters into pens and slaughtering them by the thousands
像削筆一樣砍他們，數以千計地屠殺他們
is also treating men like beasts.
與像訓野獸一樣訓男人沒什麼兩樣
The slaves you freed,
你釋放的奴隸們
brutality is all they've ever known.
只知道獸行
If you want them to know something else,
如果你想讓他們知道些別的
you'll have to show it to them.
你要示範給他們看
And repay the slavers with what? Kindness?
怎麼酬謝他們呢？仁慈？
A fine? A stern warning?
罰款？警告？
It's tempting to see your enemies as evil, all of them,
把所有的敵人都看成惡人是很誘人
but there's good and evil on both sides in every war ever fought.
但在任何戰爭中，雙方都有好人和惡人
Let the priests argue over good and evil.
讓祭祀們去討論好人和惡人
Slavery is real.
奴隸制是事實
I can end it. I will end it.
我可以並且將會制止它
And I will end those behind it.
也會制止其根源
I sold men into slavery, Khaleesi.
我販賣過奴隸，卡麗熙
And now you are helping me show them to freedom.
但現在你幫助我還他們自由
I wouldn't be here to help you if Ned Stark had done to me
如果奈德·史塔克像你對淵凱的領主那樣對我
what you want to do to the masters of Yunkai.
我就不會在這裏了
The man who came to me the other day about burying his father.
前幾天找我談埋葬父親事情的那個人
Hizdahr zo Loraq?
西茨達拉·佐·洛拉克？
He will accompany the Second Sons
他會伴隨次子團
and serve as my ambassador to Yunkai.
作為我的大使去淵凱
He will tell the masters what has happened in Meereen.
告訴領主們彌林發生的事情
He will explain the choice they have before them.
解釋他們面臨的選擇
They can live in my new world
他們可以在我的新世界活下去
or they can die in their old one.
或者在他們的舊世界死去
Well, go and catch Daario before he leaves.
快在達裏奧離開之前找到他
Tell him I changed my mind.
告訴他我改變主意了
Yes, Khaleesi.
是的，卡麗熙
No.
不
Tell him you changed my mind.
告訴他你讓我改主意了
Rat cunts.
龜孫子
Fucking whore.
該死的妓女
You're doing it wrong.
<i>你處理得不對</i>
You need to burn away that horrible bit there.
你得把那糟糕的傷口燒一下
Otherwise it's gonna get infected and fester.
<i>否則會感染化膿</i>
I know you don't like fire, but if you don't do it right--
我知道你不喜歡火，但如果處理不當…
No fire.
不要火
It'll only take a second.
只要一會兒
- It won't hurt that much. - No fire!
- 不會很痛的
- 不要火！
Shut up about it.
別再提這事
Shut up about everything.
別再提任何事
Thanks to you, I'm a walking bag of silver
多虧了你，我現在在蘭尼斯特家的地盤
anywhere the Lannisters hold sway.
成了行走的銀袋了
Which is everywhere between where we are now
而我們現在就身處此地
and where we're going.
我們要去的地方也是
I'm as stupid as that hog you stuck back in the village,
我跟你困在村裏的豬一樣蠢
getting myself cut and stabbed and bitten.
被人割傷，刺傷，咬傷
No reward is worth this much trouble.
沒有什麼獎勵值得這麼多麻煩
Wish I'd never laid eyes on you.
<i>真希望我從沒見過你</i>
You say your brother gave you that sword.
你說你哥哥給了你那把劍
My brother gave me this.
我哥哥給了我這個
It was just like you said a while back.
就像你說的那樣
Pressed me to the fire
<i>我被壓在火上</i>
like I was a nice juicy mutton chop.
就像我是鮮嫩多汁的羊排一樣
Why?
為什麼？
Thought I stole one of his toys.
他以為我偷了他一個玩具
I didn't steal it. I was just playing with it.
我沒偷，我只是在玩
The pain was bad.
疼痛很糟糕
The smell was worse.
氣味更糟糕
But the worst thing was that it was my brother who did it.
最糟糕的是這是我哥哥干的
My father, who protected him...
我父親護著他…
told everyone my bedding caught fire.
告訴別人我的床著火了
You think you're on your own?
你以為你只有自己一人？
Let me wash it out
至少讓我沖洗一下
and help you sew it up at least.
幫你縫起來
Bit of comfort never hurt anyone.
舒服些又無礙於人
We've been sleeping in ditches the last few weeks.
過去幾周我們都睡在溝渠裏
I think we can treat ourselves to a featherbed for the night
我認為今晚我們可以犒勞自己睡羽毛床
and a hot meal not cooked by you.
吃一頓不是你做的飯
Couldn't agree more, my lady.
萬分同意，夫人
Just don't start expecting silk underclothes.
但別期待絲綢內衣
Not working for your former lord any longer.
你已經不為你前任大人辦事了
- Yes, my lady. - Don't get drunk.
- 是，夫人
- 別喝醉了
No, my lady.
不會的，夫人
Can I get you anything else?
<i>還需要別的嗎？</i>
No, this will do nicely, thank you.
不用，這些夠了，謝謝
Kidney pie is wonderful.
腰子餡餅很棒
Thanks.
謝謝誇獎
I do my best.
我盡我所能
A good kidney pie is all about the ingredients.
好的腰子餡餅全靠原料
Flour, lard, water, eggs, milk.
<i>麵粉，豬油，水，雞蛋，牛奶</i>
Easy enough. But the meat,
都容易，但是肉
peacetime or not, getting your hands on a good bottom round steak
無論是否和平時期，都得拿到好的底部後腿肉
and calves' kidneys is not easy.
牛犢腰子也不好弄到
I mean, some people settle for plain old beef kidneys.
我是說，有些人會將就用普通老牛腰子
Got no right to cook anything, them.
他們沒資格做烹飪
Oh, and the gravy.
還有肉汁
Don't get me started on the gravy.
別讓我說肉汁
Very difficult to get right.
<i>很難弄到合適的</i>
See, a lot of people give up on the gravy.
<i>很多人放棄了肉汁</i>
You cannot give up on the gravy.
你可不能放棄肉汁啊
No gravy, no pie.
沒有肉汁，就沒有餡餅
Simple as that.
就這麼簡單
That's nice armor. Are you a knight?
盔甲不錯，你是騎士嗎？
No.
不是
Oh, it's just people with armor are usually knights.
穿盔甲的人一般都是騎士
Generally speaking.
<i>一般來說</i>
From King's Landing, though, aren't you?
<i>不過，你是君臨城來的吧？</i>
From there myself originally. Flea Bottom born and bred.
<i>我也是那裏來的，跳蚤窩土生土長</i>
What brings you to these parts?
<i>你們為什麼來這裏？</i>
We're looking for someone.
我們在找人
Someone in particular? Maybe they came in here.
特別的人？也許他們來過這兒
A lot of people come in here. Just the other day we had 17--
很多人來過這兒，前幾天有17個…
A girl, tall, red hair, very pretty.
一個女孩，高個子，紅頭髮，很漂亮
Her name is Sansa Stark, but she may be using a different name.
她叫珊莎·史塔克，但她可能會用別的名字
Starks?
史塔克？
What, like them lot from "Winterhell"?
就是凜冬城那些人的姓？
No, ain't seen anyone like that.
沒有，沒見過那樣的人
I heard they was all traitors.
我聽說他們都是叛徒
Don't need no traitors in here.
這裏不需要叛徒
I pledged my life to their mother Catelyn Stark.
<i>我用生命向她們的母親凱特琳·史塔克起誓</i>
I swore to her I'd bring her daughters home.
我向她發誓會帶她的女兒們回家
Sure I can't get you a bit more kidney pie?
確定不要餡餅了嗎？
What?
怎麼了？
It's nothing, my lady.
沒什麼，夫人
You wouldn't be screwing your face up like that if it was nothing.
你沒事不會那樣抬著頭
Don't want to offend, my lady. Truly, I don't.
無意冒犯，夫人，真的
You're not interesting enough to be offensive.
你想冒犯還不夠格
The Lannisters want Lady Sansa.
蘭尼斯特家想抓到珊莎小姐
The Lannisters have money.
蘭尼斯特家有錢
People kill for money.
人會為了錢殺人
I don't think we should be telling people
我認為我們不應該告訴別人
we're searching for Lady Sansa.
我們在找珊莎小姐
My lady. My lord. Could I have a word?
夫人，大人，能說句話嗎？
What about? Not kidney pie.
什麼事？別說腰子餡餅了
You seem like a proper lady.
<i>你像是有教養的小姐</i>
Someone who could be trusted.
<i>值得信任</i>
I never met no Sansa Stark.
我沒見過珊莎·史塔克
But I know her sister...
但我認識她妹妹…
Arya.
艾莉亞
No one's seen Arya Stark since her father was beheaded.
她父親被砍頭後就沒人見過艾莉亞·史塔克了
She's presumed dead.
大家都認為她死了
She weren't when I last spoke to her.
我上次跟她說話時她還沒死
When was that?
什麼時候？
Heading up north with the Night's Watch.
<i>跟守夜人一起北上</i>
She was all dressed up as a boy.
她打扮成男孩
Like your ladyship, only without the armor.
和小姐你一樣，只是沒穿盔甲
Going by the name Arry.
<i>化名阿利</i>
- So what happened to her? - Well--
她發生什麼事了？
The quick version.
長話短說
The Lannisters took us prisoner.
蘭尼斯特抓了我們
We escaped.
我們逃跑了
The Brotherhood took us prisoner.
兄弟會抓了我們
They sold me to the innkeep.
他們把我賣給旅店老闆
They were gonna sell Arya to her mother at Riverrun
<i>他們要把阿利和另一個囚犯</i>
along with another prisoner.
<i>賣給她奔流城的母親</i>
Big ugly fellow. Foul mouth
醜陋的大塊頭，嘴臭
and a face like a half-burnt ham.
臉像烤得半熟的火腿
- Not friendly. - The Hound.
- <i>很不友好</i>
- 獵狗
That's the one.
就是他
If you find her, could you give her this?
如果你找到她，能不能把這個給她？
She liked the last one I gave her,
她很喜歡我上次給她做的那個
but, well, this one turned out better.
不過這個更好
Um, you were saying?
你剛剛說什麼來著？
Her mother's dead, grandfather's dead,
<i>她母親死了，祖父死了</i>
Walder Frey is the new lord of Riverrun.
瓦德·佛雷是奔流城的新領主
The Brotherhood isn't going to Riverrun.
兄弟會不會去奔流城
They'll take her to the Eyrie, my lady.
他們會帶她去鷹巢城，夫人
Why the Eyrie?
為什麼是鷹巢城？
Her aunt, Lysa Arryn.
他姨母，萊莎·艾林
Catelyn Stark's sister.
凱特琳·史塔克的妹妹
She's Arya's last living relative with money.
她是艾莉亞最後一個在世又有錢的親戚
She hates the Lannisters.
她恨蘭尼斯特
Lord Tyrion made sure I knew
提利昂大人教我記住
which house married which and who hated who.
哪個家族與哪個家族聯姻，誰恨誰
Sansa could be there, too.
珊莎可能也在那裏
Aye, my lady.
是的，夫人
Could be.
也許
You sure about this?
你確定該走那？
No.
不確定
I imagined you'd be back at the brothel at this hour.
還以為這會兒你會在妓院呢
I did spend some time with an absolutely stunning
我前幾天的確在一個漂亮的金髮妓女那裏
blonde the other day.
待過一會兒
Mm, do tell.
說吧
I've got every kind of filth down here
我什麼齷齪事都遇到了
except the kind I like.
就是沒有我喜歡的那種
Your sister.
你姐姐
Cersei approached me.
瑟曦找過我
We spoke a great deal about her daughter.
<i>我們就她女兒談了很多</i>
How worried your sister is about her.
你姐姐真的很擔心她
She was trying very hard to pretend
<i>她竭力假裝</i>
she had not come to sway me against you.
<i>她不是來說服我對付你的</i>
I think she may have even believed it herself.
<i>我認為她可能自己都信了</i>
Making honest feelings do dishonest work
給人感覺正直，行為卻不正直
is one of her many gifts.
是她眾多的天賦之一
It was difficult for her to hide her true intentions.
對她來說隱藏真實意圖很難
It is rare to meet a Lannister
遇到一個跟我一樣希望蘭尼斯特死的
who shares my enthusiasm for dead Lannisters.
蘭尼斯特真是稀奇
She desperately wants to see you killed.
她迫切想看你死
She didn't need to bother you.
她不需要麻煩你
It looks as though I've taken care of that myself.
看來好像我已經自己解決了自己
The joy she will feel
<i>當我的腦袋離開我的脖子時</i>
when my head leaves my neck.
<i>她會感到愉悅</i>
She's wanted this for a long time.
這種愉悅她期待很久了
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道
We met, you and I.
<i>我們以前見過</i>
Many years ago.
很多年前
I think I would have remembered that.
那我應該會記得
Unlikely. You had just been born.
不會，那時你剛出生
Our father brought me and my sister Elia with him
我父親帶著我和我姐姐伊莉亞
on a visit to Casterly Rock.
來訪問凱巖城
My first time away from Dorne.
<i>是我第一次離開多恩</i>
I didn't like anything about the Rock.
我不喜歡凱巖城的一切
Not the food, not the weather,
不喜歡食物，不喜歡天氣
not your accents.
不喜歡你們的口音
Nothing.
不喜歡一切
But the biggest disappointment...
但最失望的…
you.
是你
You and my family have more in common than you might admit.
你和我們家族的共同點比你所承認的更多
The whole way from Dorne
<i>從多恩來的一路上</i>
all anyone talked about was the monster
所有人談論的都是
that had been born to Tywin Lannister.
泰溫·蘭尼斯特生的怪胎
A head twice the size of his body,
<i>頭有身體的兩倍大</i>
a tail between his legs,
<i>兩腿之間有尾巴</i>
claws, one red eye,
有爪子，一隻紅眼
the privates of both a girl and a boy.
既有女孩也有男孩的生殖器
That would have made things so much easier.
真是那樣就好辦多了
When we met your sister, she promised she would show you to us.
<i>我們見到你姐姐時，她答應帶我們去看你</i>
Every day we would ask.
每天我們都問她
Every day she would say, "Soon."
每天她都說「快了」
Then she and your brother
然後她和你哥哥
took us to your nursery and...
帶我們去了你的嬰兒房…
she unveiled the freak.
她揭開了那個怪胎的布
Your head was a bit large.
<i>你的頭有點大</i>
Your arms and legs were a bit small,
<i>你的手和腿有點小</i>
but no claw.
但沒有爪子
No red eye. No tail between your legs.
沒有紅眼睛，腿中間也沒有尾巴
Just a tiny pink cock.
只有個小粉雞巴
We didn't try to hide our disappointment.
<i>我們沒有掩飾失望之情</i>
"That's not a monster," I told Cersei.
<i>我跟瑟曦說：「這不是魔鬼」</i>
"That's just a baby."
「只是個嬰孩」
And she said, "He killed my mother."
<i>而她說：「他害死了我母親」</i>
And she pinched your little cock so hard,
<i>她使勁捏著你的小雞巴</i>
I thought she might pull it off.
<i>我以為她會拽下來</i>
Until your brother made her stop.
<i>但你哥哥制止了她</i>
"It doesn't matter," she told us.
<i>她跟我們說：「無所謂」</i>
"Everyone says he will die soon.
<i>「大家都說他很快就會死」</i>
I hope they are right.
<i>「希望他們說的是真的」</i>
He should not have lived this long."
<i>「他不應該活這麼久」</i>
Well...
好吧…
sooner or later, Cersei always gets what she wants.
瑟曦總能得到她想要的
And what about what I want?
那我想要的呢？
Justice
公正
for my sister and her children.
為我姐姐和她的孩子
If you want justice,
如果你想要公正
you've come to the wrong place.
那可來錯地方了
I disagree.
不見得
I've come to the perfect place.
我來得正合適
I want to bring those who have wronged me to justice.
我想把折磨過我的人繩之以法
And all those who have wronged me are right here.
而所有折磨過我的人就在這
I will begin with Ser Gregor Clegane,
我要先拿格雷果·克裏岡開刀
who killed my sister's children
<i>他殺了我姐姐的孩子</i>
and then raped her with their blood still on his hands
用沾著孩子們的血的手強姦了她
before killing her, too.
之後也殺了她
I will be your champion.
我會當你的比武代表
Hello, Robin.
你好，羅賓
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
I'm building my home, Winterfell.
我在建我的家，臨冬城
At least I think I am.
可能不太像
I haven't been back there in a very long time.
我很久沒有回去了
Why did you leave?
你為什麼離開？
It's a long story.
說來話長
I stay here in the Eyrie.
我就待在鷹巢城
Mother says it's dangerous on the roads and I have to keep myself safe
母親說外面很危險，我必須保證自己安全
because I'm the Lord of the Vale
因為我是谷地的領主
and the Lord of the Vale is a very important person.
谷地的領主是非常重要的人物
Yes, you certainly are.
是啊，你當然是
When will you go back?
你什麼時候回去？
Probably never.
也許回不去了
My family doesn't live there anymore
我家已經不住在那了
and someone burned it down.
而且有人把它燒燬了
Oh.
哦
Does Winterfell have a Moon Door?
臨冬城有月門嗎？
No, I'm afraid not.
恐怕沒有
It's not high up in the mountains. It's down on the ground.
臨冬城不在高山上，而是建在地面
That sounds dangerous.
感覺很危險
- How do you make people fly? - We don't.
- 那你怎麼讓人飛走？
- 我不那麼做
What do you do with all the bad people
那你怎麼處置壞蛋
and the scary people and the people you don't like?
和討厭的人啊？
I never did anything with them at all.
我從沒處置過那些人
Girls didn't take part in that where I came from.
在我家，女孩不許參與這種事
Well, I'm Lord of the Vale.
我是谷地的領主
When I grow up, I'll be able to fly anybody who bothers me.
等我長大了，誰煩我我就能讓誰飛走
Or you. When we get married,
你也能，等我們結婚了
you can tell me if you don't like somebody
你不喜歡誰，可以告訴我
and then we can bring them back here and, whoosh!
我們就把他們帶來，然後嗖！
Right through the Moon Door.
推下月門
I like the sound of that.
聽上去不錯
Let's put a Moon Door in your Winterfell.
我們在你的臨冬城上也弄個月門吧！
All right.
好的
It can go in here in this big tower.
可以在這個高塔裏弄一個
Careful. You've ruined it.
小心！你把它弄壞了
Now I'm going to have to rebuild the whole thing.
我只能全部重建
- I didn't ruin it. - You did.
- 我沒弄壞它
- 你有
It was already ruined because it didn't have a Moon Door.
本來就是壞的，因為沒有月門
I was fixing it.
我是在修理
Knocking things down isn't fixing them.
把東西撞倒不叫修理
- It's ruining them. - I didn't ruin it!
- 叫破壞
- 我沒弄壞！
- You're being stupid. - I didn't ruin it!
- 你無理取鬧
- 我沒弄壞！
Robin, I'm sorry, I--
羅賓，對不起，我…
Children.
<i>小孩子</i>
- I hit him. - Yes, I saw.
- <i>我打了他</i>
- 是，我看見了
I shouldn't have done that.
我不該打他
No, his mother should have
是不該，但他母親
a long time ago.
早就該打他了
Consider it a step in the right direction.
就當是為了教育他吧
If he tells Aunt Lysa...
要是他告訴了萊莎阿姨…
Let me worry about Aunt Lysa.
讓我來解決萊莎阿姨
I was trying to remember what everything looked like.
我只想記下臨冬城的模樣
I'll never see it again.
我永遠也見不到了
A lot can happen between now and never.
在現在與永遠之間，有無數可能
If you want to build a better home,
要是你想建一個更好的家
first you must demolish the old one.
首先你必須拆毀舊的家
Why did you really kill Joffrey?
你究竟為什麼要殺喬佛裏？
Tell me why.
告訴我
I loved your mother more than you could ever know.
我對你母親的愛，遠超你所想
Given the opportunity, what do we do to those
如果有機會，我們該怎樣對待
who've hurt the ones we love?
傷害了我們心愛之人的人？
In a better world,
假如有一個更美好的世界
one where love
在那裏愛能夠克服
could overcome strength and duty,
力量和責任
you might have been my child.
你本可能會是我的孩子
But we don't live in that world.
但我們沒生活在那個世界
You're more beautiful than she ever was.
你比她還美
Lord Baelish...
貝裏席大人…
Call me Petyr.
叫我培提爾
You wanted to see me, Aunt Lysa?
<i>你想見我，萊莎阿姨？</i>
Come here, Sansa.
過來，珊莎
Do you know how far the fall is?
你知道這有多高嗎？
No.
不知道
Neither do I, precisely.
<i>我也不知道精確高度</i>
Hundreds of feet.
<i>幾百尺吧</i>
It's fascinating
很有意思
what happens to bodies when they hit the rocks from such a height.
從這麼高掉下去摔在石頭上
The impact breaks them right apart.
身體會馬上撞碎
Like eggs dropped on the floor.
就像雞蛋掉在地板上一樣
Sometimes pieces remain intact.
有時有幾片完整的
You'll find the head sitting on its own.
頭落在了一邊
Every hair in place.
頭髮都還在
Blue eyes staring at nothing.
藍眼睛空洞無物
I know what you did.
我知道你幹了什麼
I'm so sorry, Aunt Lysa.
我很抱歉，萊莎阿姨
I never should have hit Robin, I know it. I promise it won't happen--
我不該打羅賓，我懂，我保證不會再…
Don't be coy with me, you little whore.
別跟我忸怩作態，你個小賤人
You kissed him. You kissed Petyr.
你親了他，你親了培提爾
- I didn't. You don't understand. - I saw you.
- 我沒有，你不知道
- 我看見你們了
You can't lie to me because I saw it with my own eyes.
你騙不了我，因為我親眼看見了
- He kissed me. I pulled away. - Liar!
- 是他親我，我推開了
- 騙子！
Whore! He is mine!
賤人！他是我的！
My father, my husband, my sister,
我父親，我丈夫，我姐姐
they all stood between us and now they're all dead.
都阻礙著我們，但現在他們都死了
That's what happens to people who stand between Petyr and me.
阻礙我和培提爾就是這個下場
Look down!
低頭看！
Look down! Look down! Look down!
低頭看！低頭看！低頭看！
Lysa!
<i>萊莎！</i>
Let her go.
放開她
You want her?
你想要她？
This empty-headed child?
這個愚蠢的小孩？
Let her go.
放開她
She's just like her mother. She'll never love you.
她跟她媽一樣，她絕不會愛你
I lied for you.
我為你撒謊
I killed for you.
<i>我為你殺人</i>
Why did you bring her here? Why?
為什麼你要帶她來？為什麼？
I'll send her away.
我會把她送走的
I swear on my life.
我以生命發誓
I swear to all the gods.
我向所有神發誓
Let her go, Lysa.
放開她，萊莎
Oh, my sweet wife.
噢，我親愛的妻子
My sweet, silly wife.
我親愛的傻妻子
I have only loved one woman...
我這一生中
only one,
只愛過一個女人…
my entire life.
只有一個
Your sister.
就是你姐姐
-=TLF字幕組=-
謝謝觀賞
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/